njcourts.gov 2017-10-14

# Privacy Policy

This statement is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect, use and safeguard information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using the Judiciary's web site. It will be continuously assessed against new technologies, business practices and the needs of our visitors.

* * *

## Section A. Information Collected and How it is Used

### 1\. Web Site Information Collected and Stored Automatically

If you do nothing during your visit but browse through the Web site, read pages, or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit automatically. This information does not identify you personally. We automatically collect and store only the following information about your visit: 

>   * The Internet domain (for example, "xcompany.com" if you use a private Internet access account, or "yourschool.edu" if you connect from a university's domain) and IP address (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are browsing the Internet) from which you access our Web site;
>   * The type of browser and operating system used to access our site;
>   * The date and time you access our site;
>   * The pages you visit; and
>   * If you linked to the New Jersey Judiciary Web site from another Web site, the address of that Web site. 
> 

We use this information to help us make our site more useful to visitors - to learn about the number of visitors to our site and the types of technology our visitors use. We do not track or record information about individuals and their visits. IP addresses are not linked to identifiable information.

### 2\. Personal Information

"Personal information" is information about a natural person that identifies a specific individual. Personal information includes such things as an individual's name, address, and phone number. A domain name or Internet protocol address is not considered personal information.

We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us by sending us e-mail, participating in a survey, paying a traffic ticket online, or completing an online form. You may choose not to contact us by e-mail, participate in a survey, pay your traffic ticket online, or provide any personal information using an online form. Your choice not to participate in these activities will not impair your ability to browse the Judiciary's Web site and read or download any information posted on the site.

If you choose to provide us with personal information -- by sending an e-mail, or by filling out a form with your personal information and submitting it to us through our Web site -- we use that information to respond to your message and to help us get you the information you have requested. We share the information you give us with another government agency only if your inquiry relates to that agency, or as otherwise required by law. Moreover, we do not create individual profiles with the information you provide or give it to any private organizations. The New Jersey Judiciary does not collect information for commercial marketing or sell any information provided by users through this Web site to third parties.

The Judiciary does not plan to divulge personal information collected or information disclosed voluntarily, but may be required to do so pursuant to State or Federal law.

If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted it, please contact the individual shown in the "Contact Information" section of this privacy policy.

### 3\. Credit Card or Financial Information

If you choose to pay filing fees, registration fees, continuing learning, traffic ticket fines or any other judicially imposed financial obligation via an on-line Judiciary application, any personal information you submit will be used solely to update our court files to reflect that your payment has been made. Credit card/Debit card information is stored securely and in a confidential manner, and will be used solely for administrative purposes (e.g. in the event that you wish to revise a particular credit/debit card transaction).

The use of, and access to your personal information is restricted to those employees who need to know that information to provide services or support to you. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect your personal information.

### 4\. E-mail Privacy warning

E-mail is not a secure medium. Personal information sent via the Internet can be intercepted. You may, therefore, wish to reconsider the advisability of sending messages that contain highly sensitive, personal information to this Internet address.

### 5\. Kid's Page

The New Jersey Judiciary Kids' Page encourages children to learn about government, the court system, and the law. No personal information is collected or stored. Visitors to the Kids' Page are invited to submit their comments and suggestions. We specifically ask children to get their parents' permission before providing any information on line -- at our site or any other site -- and hope that parents will always be involved in those decisions. Most importantly, when children do provide information through the New Jersey Judiciary Web site, it is used only to enable us to respond to the writer, and not to create profiles of children.

## Section B. Public Access to Information

All information posted on the Judiciary's Web site is public information that is subject to inspection and copying by members of the public.

## Section C. Cookies

Cookies are simple text files stored on your computer by Internet Web sites to help identify users and customize user experience. The New Jersey Judiciary Web site does not use cookies.

## Section D. Security

The New Jersey Judiciary, as developer and manager of this Web site has taken several steps to safeguard the integrity of its data and prevent unauthorized access to information maintained. These measures are designed and intended to prevent corruption of data, block unknown or unauthorized access to our systems and information, and to provide reasonable protection of private and personal information in our possession. This Web site takes every precaution to protect users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, their information is protected both online and offline. When we ask users to enter personal information (such as credit card number), that information is encrypted and is protected with encryption software. While we use encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also protect user information offline.

## Section E. Disclaimer

The New Jersey Judiciary's Web site and materials may contain hypertext or links to other Internet computer sites which are not owned, operated, controlled or reviewed by the Judiciary. These links are provided solely as a courtesy and convenience to you, the visitor. When you link to one of these sites, you are no longer on the New Jersey Judiciary Web site and this privacy policy will not apply. When you link to another Web site, you are subject to the privacy policy of that web site.

### Section F. Contact Information

To offer comments about the New Jersey Judiciary Web site: 

**New Jersey Judiciary, Office of Communications and Community Relations**  
PO Box 039  
Trenton, New Jersey 08625  
**Phone** : [609-815-2910](tel:609-815-2910)  

To offer comments about this privacy statement:

**New Jersey Judiciary, Information Security Unit**  
PO Box 037   
Trenton, New Jersey 08625
